<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>viridis on %&gt;% dreams</title>
    <link>/tags/viridis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in viridis on %&gt;% dreams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/viridis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an R Package for School District Shapefiles</title>
      <link>/blog/leaid-shapefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/leaid-shapefiles/</guid>
      <description>I would like to introduce {leaidr}, a package for mapping U.S. School District shapefiles!
Inspired by my coauthor Joshua Rosenberg, the goal of {leaidr} is to facilitate the download and use of school district shapefiles.
School districts in the U.S. have an associated local education agency identification numbers (LEAID) used in National Center for Education Statistics (NCES) Common Core of Data. These are very useful because if you have other datasets with NCES ID’s, then you can easily join them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disaggregating Minneapolis Public Schools Data</title>
      <link>/blog/why-disaggregate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-disaggregate-data/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I am a data analyst committed to nonprofit work with the aim of reducing racial and socioeconomic inequities. Data, and in particular disaggregated data, can provide measures of the equity of a system, process, or program. Displaying data by subgroups is an important step in any data team’s equity journey, and exploring these data beyond averages can highlight the most prominent equity needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I define what disaggregated data is and how it can inform teams on their equity work. Then, I run various cuts on Minneapolis Public Schools data. The district’s reporting of the composition of their schools provides an excellent opportunity to explore inequities in a system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>