<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isabella Velásquez</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Isabella Velásquez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking A Peek into My Hiking Data</title>
      <link>/blog/average-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/average-hike/</guid>
      <description>I moved to Seattle at the end of 2016 and since then have done over 100 hikes (depending on your definition of ‘a hike’!). I must admit I’ve been abysmal at tracking any data regarding my hiking activity beyond a Google spreadsheet, despite the ubiquity of trail tracking apps that exist.
Recently, I signed up on AllTrails to start collecting data on my hikes. The Pro service offers many wonderful features, including the ability to download GPX data on hikes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming PDF&#39;s into Useful Tables</title>
      <link>/blog/snap-expenditures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/snap-expenditures/</guid>
      <description>Way back in 2016, the USDA released a study entitled “Foods Typically Purchased by Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) Households,” including a summary, final report, and appendices. Per the USDA’s description:
This study uses calendar year 2011 point-of-sale transaction data from a leading grocery retailer to examine the food choices of SNAP and non-SNAP households.
At the time though, I was most interested in looking at the appendices data - 263 pages full of tables detailing the commodities and categories of food bought by both families served and not served by SNAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disaggregating Minneapolis Public Schools Data</title>
      <link>/blog/why-disaggregate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-disaggregate-data/</guid>
      <description>I am a data analyst committed to nonprofit work with the aim of reducing racial and socioeconomic inequities. Data, and in particular disaggregated data, can provide measures of the equity of a system, process, or program. Displaying data by subgroups is an important step in any data team’s equity journey, and exploring these data beyond averages can highlight the most prominent equity needs.
In this post, I define what disaggregated data is and how it can inform teams on their equity work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from an R-Centric Program</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>The new school year is right around the corner and I have gotten a few requests from new students entering a Data Science or Analyst program to talk about my experience in graduate school. I graduated with a Masters of Science in Analytics from the University of Chicago in June 2016. It was an amazing experience that helped propel me into a new career but there are definitely things I wish I had known or would have done differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wizehiver</title>
      <link>/itemized/item1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/item1/</guid>
      <description>wizehiver      
wizehiver is currently a work in progress.
The Zengine API, created by WizeHive, is a cloud-based platform that can organize the collection, review, and management of data and applications for grants and other business processes. The goal of wizehiver is to build functionality to:
 Input and manage Zengine RESTful API tokens Get available API resources Process API response content into analysis-ready tibbles  The wizehiver package has no relationship or affiliation with, sponsorship, or endorsement by WizeHive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visualizations</title>
      <link>/itemized/visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/visualizations/</guid>
      <description>Energy Generation by U.S. State Code</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>