<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>%&gt;% dreams</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on %&gt;% dreams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an R Package for School District Shapefiles</title>
      <link>/blog/leaid-shapefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/leaid-shapefiles/</guid>
      <description>I would like to introduce {leaidr}, a package for mapping U.S. School District shapefiles!
Inspired by my coauthor Joshua Rosenberg, the goal of {leaidr} is to facilitate the download and use of school district shapefiles.
School districts in the U.S. have associated local education agency identification numbers (LEAID) used in the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES) Common Core of Data. These are very useful because if you have other datasets with NCES ID’s, then you can (sometimes easily) join them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/blog/three-shiny-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/three-shiny-things/</guid>
      <description>I’ve commonly heard (and experienced) that Shiny apps “look Shiny”, as in, it’s really clear when you look at an app whether or not it is a Shiny app. It may be the font, layout, or interactivity, but something about them is uniform across most of the apps that you see (I could argue the same for most Tableau dashboards too…). This is not to say that the “Shiny” look is not good, but I have been trying to find ways of making them “prettier” - more aesthetically pleasing, and a little less uniform than the standard template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You CRAN Do It</title>
      <link>/blog/you-cran-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/you-cran-do-it/</guid>
      <description>As the @WeAreRLadies curator, I asked the Twitterverse for advice when submitting to CRAN for the first time. Many people replied and offer their tips, experience, and well wishes. I have summarized everybody’s replies below. THANK YOU all for participating!
Here’s what to expect when succeeding to get your package on CRAN!
 I don&amp;#39;t know you, but I believe in you 🤩
&amp;mdash; Travis Dawry (@tdawry) February 14, 2020   Read the Official CRAN Documentation … which is Writing R Extensions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mise-en-Place: Everything in its Place</title>
      <link>/blog/mis-en-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mis-en-place/</guid>
      <description>I got to be the @WeAreRLadies curator for the week of February 10th and it was a great experience to get feedback from a wider swath of the R community. One question I posed was how people organize the folders within their projects, and I got a lot of engagement! For this blogpost, I categorize the common themes from these different resources and then list them all out at the end of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breath of the Wild Weapon Dendrogram</title>
      <link>/blog/botw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/botw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Things I Always Google When Using ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/things-i-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/things-i-google/</guid>
      <description>I often use {ggplot2} to create graphs but there are certain things I always have to Google. I figured I’d create a post for quick reference for myself but I’d love to hear what you always have to look up!
 Remove the Legend Change Legend Title and Labels Manually Change Colors Remove X Axis Labels Start the Y Axis at a Specific Number Use Scales on the Y Axis  library(tidyverse) knitr::opts_chunk$set(out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Modal School District</title>
      <link>/blog/modal-district/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/modal-district/</guid>
      <description>My good friend Ryan Estrellado recommended an NPR Planet Money podcast episode on the “Modal American.” Working with Ben Casselman, Planet Money explored the most ‘typical’ American. It was a fantastic, engaging episode about a common statistical technique that I’ve never seen applied in this way before. They ran the numbers on a variety of demographic variables to see what group is the most common in the U.S. (I highly recommend the episode - it’s pretty surprising!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking A Peek into My Hiking Data</title>
      <link>/blog/average-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/average-hike/</guid>
      <description>I moved to Seattle at the end of 2016 and since then have done over 100 hikes (depending on your definition of ‘a hike’!). I must admit I’ve been abysmal at tracking any data regarding my hiking activity beyond a Google spreadsheet, despite the ubiquity of trail tracking apps that exist.
Recently, I signed up on AllTrails to start collecting data on my hikes. The Pro service offers many wonderful features, including the ability to download GPX data on hikes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming PDF&#39;s into Useful Tables</title>
      <link>/blog/snap-expenditures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/snap-expenditures/</guid>
      <description>Way back in 2016, the USDA released a study entitled “Foods Typically Purchased by Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) Households,” including a summary, final report, and appendices. Per the USDA’s description:
 This study uses calendar year 2011 point-of-sale transaction data from a leading grocery retailer to examine the food choices of SNAP and non-SNAP households.
 At the time though, I was most interested in looking at the appendices data - 263 pages full of tables detailing the commodities and categories of food bought by both families served and not served by SNAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disaggregating Minneapolis Public Schools Data</title>
      <link>/blog/why-disaggregate-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-disaggregate-data/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I am a data analyst committed to nonprofit work with the aim of reducing racial and socioeconomic inequities. Data, and in particular disaggregated data, can provide measures of the equity of a system, process, or program. Displaying data by subgroups is an important step in any data team’s equity journey, and exploring these data beyond averages can highlight the most prominent equity needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I define what disaggregated data is and how it can inform teams on their equity work. Then, I run various cuts on Minneapolis Public Schools data. The district’s reporting of the composition of their schools provides an excellent opportunity to explore inequities in a system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You&#39;re Getting a Masters in Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>The new school year is right around the corner and I have gotten a few requests from new students entering a Data Science or Analyst program to talk about my experience in graduate school. I graduated with a Masters of Science in Analytics from the University of Chicago in June 2016. It was an amazing experience that helped propel me into a new career but there are definitely things I wish I had known or would have done differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wizehiver</title>
      <link>/itemized/item1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/item1/</guid>
      <description>wizehiver      
wizehiver is currently a work in progress.
The Zengine API, created by WizeHive, is a cloud-based platform that can organize the collection, review, and management of data and applications for grants and other business processes. The goal of wizehiver is to build functionality to:
 Input and manage Zengine RESTful API tokens Get available API resources Process API response content into analysis-ready tibbles  The wizehiver package has no relationship or affiliation with, sponsorship, or endorsement by WizeHive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>talks</title>
      <link>/itemized/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/talks/</guid>
      <description>2020-05-08 Package Management in R Seattle useR Group
2019-07-16 Taking a Peek at Hiking Data Using R R-Ladies Seattle
2018-07-23 Blogdown for What R-Ladies Seattle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visualizations</title>
      <link>/itemized/visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/itemized/visualizations/</guid>
      <description>Energy Generation by U.S. State  Energy ⚡🏭💧generation by U.S. state, 1990 - 2017 using the #geofacet package #rstats
Code: https://t.co/ARpYK7snSp pic.twitter.com/DrtKcOWJqt
&amp;mdash; Isabella Velásquez (@ivelasq3) June 6, 2019    U.S. Public High School Start Times  U.S. Public High School Start Times from @EdNCES ☀️I went to one of those unfortunate Texan high schools that start at *7:25* in the morning. I&amp;#39;m still sleepy.https://t.co/fdhyowIu09 #rstats #dataedu #ggplot2 #maps #showtext pic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>