<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ggplot2 on %&gt;% dreams</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ggplot2 on %&gt;% dreams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What It Takes to Tidy Census Data</title>
      <link>/blog/tidying-census-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidying-census-data/</guid>
      <description>The U.S. Census releases data on their Household Pulse Survey. These data are super interesting and cover a range of important topics, particularly those related to the COVID-19 pandemic.
First of all, let me clarify that I think that the work that the Census does is amazing and I am so glad that these data are available. But, when you download the data, you will see that it is a highly stylized Excel spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an R Package for School District Shapefiles</title>
      <link>/blog/leaid-shapefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/leaid-shapefiles/</guid>
      <description>I would like to introduce {leaidr}, a package for mapping U.S. School District shapefiles!
Inspired by my coauthor Joshua Rosenberg, the goal of {leaidr} is to facilitate the download and use of school district shapefiles.
School districts in the U.S. have associated local education agency identification numbers (LEAID) used in the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES) Common Core of Data. These are very useful because if you have other datasets with NCES ID’s, then you can (sometimes easily) join them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mise-en-Place: Everything in its Place</title>
      <link>/blog/mis-en-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mis-en-place/</guid>
      <description>I got to be the @WeAreRLadies curator for the week of February 10th and it was a great experience to get feedback from a wider swath of the R community. One question I posed was how people organize the folders within their projects, and I got a lot of engagement! For this blogpost, I categorize the common themes from these different resources and then list them all out at the end of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breath of the Wild Weapon Dendrogram</title>
      <link>/blog/botw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/botw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Things I Always Google When Using ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/things-i-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/things-i-google/</guid>
      <description>I often use {ggplot2} to create graphs but there are certain things I always have to Google. I figured I’d create a post for quick reference for myself but I’d love to hear what you always have to look up!
 Remove the Legend Change Legend Title and Labels Manually Change Colors Remove X Axis Labels Start the Y Axis at a Specific Number Use Scales on the Y Axis  library(tidyverse) knitr::opts_chunk$set(out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>